Guide to the Presbyterian Student Center Records, 1962-1969
Duke University. University Archives
Presbyterian Student Center records 1962-1969
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Presbyterian Student Center
1 linear foot Extent: 1000 Items
The Westminster Fellowship was created in 1946 as a way to organize Presbyterian students at Duke University. By the early 1960s, the Presbyterian Student Center was built. The collection contains committee files for Presbyterian Campus Christian Life, Synod Campus Christian Life, and Advisory Committee for the Presbyterian Synod of North Carolian, as well as, printed materials for regional conferences and workshops. The material ranges in date from 1962-1969.
UA.31.04.0008
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Presbyterian Student Center Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1975.
Historical Note
In 1946, Dr. Dwight M. Chalmers, minister at Trinity Avenue Presbyterian Church, developed the idea that the Presbyterian students at Duke University should be organized; and therefore, the Westminster Fellowship was born. However, because he left Durham within two years, the project floundered.
In the mid 1950's Dr. Regen and Dr. Bennett were instrumental in persuading the Synod of North Carolina to maintain the project. They also started, a few years later, a campaign to raise money to build a Presbyterian Student Center. Mr. Charles Dukes from First Presbyterian Church was chairman of the building committee.
Collection Overview
The collection contains committee files for Presbyterian Campus Christian Life, Synod Campus Christian Life, and Advisory Committee for the Presbyterian Synod of North Carolian, as well as, printed materials for regional conferences and workshops. The material ranges in date from 1962-1969 and is arranged into two series: Committees and Miscellaneous.
Subject Headings
Duke University. Presbyterian Student Center; Duke University -- Religion; Duke University -- Students -- Religious activities
Related Material
United Methodist-Presbyterian Ministry Records, 1933-1974
Duke University Archives
Religious Life Reference Collection, 1937-ongoing
Duke University Archives
Minister to the University (Dean of the Chapel) records, 1940-1984
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Committees, (.75 boxes)
  - Campus Christian Life Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Campus Christian Life - Synod of North Carolina, subcommittee meetings, Apr. 7-8, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Presbyterian Campus Christian Life Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Presbyterian Campus Christian Life Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Presbyterian Campus Christian Life Committee, 1968 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Presbyterian Campus Christian Life Committee, 1968 (2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Presbyterian Campus Christian Life Committee - Chaplain Search (Box 1)
  - Presbyterian Campus Christian Life Committee, Subcommittee on Personnel (Box 1)
  - Presbyterian Campus Christian Life Committee, Westminster Vice Chairman (Box 1)
  - Presbyterian Synod of North Carolina Advisory Committee (Box 1)
  - Synod Campus Christian Life Committee (1 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Synod Campus Christian Life Committee (2 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Synod Campus Christian Life Committee (3 of 3) (Box 1)
  - Synod Campus Christian Life Committee, Apr. 30 - May 1, 1968 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Synod Campus Christian Life Committee, Apr. 30 - May 1, 1968 (2of 2) (Box 1)
  - Synod Campus Christian Life Committee - Greenville, NC, Nov. 16-17, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Synod Campus Christian Life Committee - Raleigh, May, 1969 (1 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Synod Campus Christian Life Committee - Raleigh, May, 1969,(2 of 2) (Box 1)
  - Synod Campus Christian Life Committee, Subcommittee on Policy (Box 1)
  - Synod of North Carolina Campus Christian Life Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Synod Special Committee on Organizational Structure of Education (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous, (.25 boxes)
  - Campus Christian Life Conference - Fayetteville, NC (Box 1)
  - Joint Seminar - NC Council of Churches Committee and South East Regional Committee on United Ministries, Nov. 1, 1966 (Box 1)
  - North Carolina College - Geography Workshop, Nov. 12, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Occasional Papers (Box 1)
  - United Campus Christian Ministry (Box 1)
  - Wesminster Chimes (Box 1)
  - Westminster Workshop, Apr. 9, 1965 (Box 1)